# LYNN RICHARDS

778.987.0378

Vancouver BC, Canada

in linkedin.com/in/lynnrichards1

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Web developer with extensive experience in designing, developing, testing, and deploying applications. Demonstrated ability in leading software development projects, performing database management, and customer support. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

#### **EDUCATION**

# CareerFoundry

Vancouver, BC

**Full Stack Developer Certification** 

#### **Cornell University**

Ithaca, NY

Master of Engineering: Computer Science

#### The American University

Washington, D.C.

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- MS SQL Server, MongoDB
- CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Node, REACT, Bootstrap
- MS Office, Adobe Suite
- Git, Trello, Teamwork, Zendesk, and more...

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Fluent in English, French and Arabic.
- US Citizen with Canadian Permanent Residency.
- Avid cyclist, with top podium finishes at various races in B.C and AZ.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

### **IT Consultant - NGN Productions**

Vancouver, BC • 09/2017-09/2021

- Used Google Apps Script (GAS) to automate a film repository which allowed producers to update and filter worldwide movie releases and generate automatic weekly reports for company executives.
- Managed customer support, website maintenance and the company's cast & crew database.

# **Project manager - Cycling Components Network**

Vancouver, BC • 11/2015 - 05/2017

- Led a team of engineers through of all phases of the software development lifecycle to create cutting-edge online registration systems for clients such as *USA Cycling* and *Triathlon Canada*.
- Maintained project schedules, work breakdown structures, issue logs, and status reports ensuring timely completion of deliverables.
- Gathered, analyzed, and presented statistical membership reports for Triathlon
   Canada and The Vancouver Sun Run by writing an application that generated and
   compiled historical customers' membership data.

#### Web Developer - Self

Phoenix, AZ • 09/2009 - 11/2015

 Maintained client-server solutions for *The Cawley Company*, a worldwide provider for badge identification systems. Applications included an encrypted databasedriven badge ordering system for all *Carlson Hotel* branches, and online employee badge ordering systems for *Cintas*, and *Budget* offices nationwide.

# Corporate Quality Senior Software Engineer - Intel Corporation

Chandler, AZ • 10/1995 - 09/2006

- Responsible for the design and development of the central repository for Intel's Customer Operational Shared Resource (COSR). Contributed to each step of COSR's n-tier application development lifecycle: design, development, deployment & support.
- Product owner of Intel's Change Management Information System: a client-server
  application that automates the notification of product changes to Intel's customer
  base worldwide. Contributed to the design, development, testing & support of the
  application.